creditsavvy.com.au 2018-05-10

# Credit Savvy - Privacy Policy

### Your privacy is important

At Credit Savvy Australia (“Credit Savvy”, “We”, “Us” and “Our”), We understand how important it is to keep any personal information We have about Our users, including visitors browsing Our site ([www.creditsavvy.com.au](https://www.creditsavvy.com.au/)) (“Site”) and registered members of the Site (“You” and “Your”) private, protected and safe. We are committed to protecting the personal information of individuals with whom We deal with.

You can be confident that We comply with the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (“Privacy Act”) and the Australian Privacy Principles for the protection and use of personal information. This Credit Savvy Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) outlines how We can collect, use, hold and disclose Your personal information.

Please read through this Privacy Policy carefully prior to accessing or using the Site. Your access or use of the Site indicates that You agree to abide by, and be bound by, this Privacy Policy and any other related policies, notices, representations or additional terms applicable to the Site, including the Credit Savvy Terms of Use. The personal information We seek to collect about You is necessary for the service We provide. If You do not allow Us to collect all of the information We require, We may not be able to deliver Our service to You.

### What kind of personal information do We collect?

If You are a visitor on the Site, We will not store any personal information You input into the Site.

If You register as a member with Us, We will collect personal information directly from You. This will include identification information such as Your full name, address, contact details, date of birth, drivers licence and passport details.

Throughout Your membership with Us, We may collect credit reporting information about You. Details of the type of credit information We receive from Experian Australia Credit Services Pty Ltd ABN 12 150 305 838 (“Experian”) is outlined in detail in the Credit Savvy Terms of Use.

We may from time to time receive and store certain automatic non-identifiable information relating to Your use of, and behaviour on the Site. This information is commonly referred to as “clickstream” information. For example, We may record information such as the areas of the Site accessed by You, the time, date and URL of the pages requested by You, Your browser software, Your IP address, and/or the previous website that You have linked to the Site from. The recording of such information enables Us to identify the areas of Our Site that are most popular and to tailor the Site accordingly.

### Why do We collect Your personal information?

We will use Your personal information for the reason We collected it and for any other reasonable business purposes in that We may database, store and process information to provide You with Our services.

We collect, use and exchange Your information so that We can:

  * establish Your identity;
  * manage Our relationship with You;
  * act as Your agent as ‘access seeker’ to obtain credit reporting information about You;
  * provide You with Your credit score and other credit reporting information;
  * adjust the products and services on the Site;
  * manage Our risks and help identify and investigate any illegal activity, such as fraud;
  * contact You, for example if We need to tell You something important or tell You about products or services We think may be of interest to You;
  * comply with Our legal and regulatory reporting obligations and assist government and law enforcement agencies or regulators;
  * conduct internal system development testing and analysis; and
  * any other customer support purposes.

We may also collect, use and exchange Your information in other ways where permitted by law.

We may hold or process Your information on servers located overseas, namely the United States, for filtering, hosting, mailing list providers, or storage purposes, reporting and analytical purposes and for system development testing purposes. If this happens, We make sure that such organisations have the appropriate data handling and security arrangements in place to ensure compliance with this Privacy Policy.

### Do We gather and combine data to get insights?

Improvements in technology enable organisations, like Us, to collect and use information to get a more integrated view of users and provide better products and services. We may combine user information with information available from a wide variety of external sources (for example census or Australian Bureau of Statistics data) to analyse the data in order to gain useful insights which can be used for any purpose.

In addition, We may provide data insights or related reports to others, for example to help them understand their customers better. These are based on aggregated information and do not contain any information that identifies You.

### Do We use information for direct marketing?

If you choose to opt-in, We may use personal information and credit reporting information We collect about You to provide direct marketing offers on products and services We think may be of interest to You, unless You tell Us not to. This may be in the form of an email or other electronic means. You may at any time choose not to receive these direct marketing communications. If this is the case, please log into Your account at [www.creditsavvy.com.au](https://www.creditsavvy.com.au/member/secure/settings) and edit the subscription preferences in Your Account Settings.

### Who do We exchange Your information with?

Generally, We disclose personal information to organisations that help Us with the operation of Our business. These may include:

  * credit reporting bodies, such as Experian Australia Credit Services Pty Ltd. For more information about how Experian use and handle Your personal information, please refer to Experian’s privacy policies at [www.experian.com.au](http://www.experian.com.au/);
  * online identity verification providers;
  * Our suppliers, agents, associates, contractors and external service providers (including, for example, call centre, stationery printing houses, mail houses, information technology, marketing agencies, and marketing research companies);
  * Our financial advisers, legal advisers or auditors;
  * regulatory bodies, government agencies and law enforcement bodies in any jurisdiction; and
  * external dispute resolution schemes.

These organisations include [Vix Verify](http://www.vixverify.com/ "Vix Verify"), [Microsoft Corp. (Azure)](https://azure.microsoft.com/en-au/), [Datacom Systems (NSW) Pty Ltd](http://datacomgroup.net/), [The Rocket Science Group LLC (Mailchimp)](http://mailchimp.com/), [Document Verification Service (DVS)](http://www.dvs.gov.au/). For more information about how they use and handle your personal information, please refer to their privacy policies.

We may also provide personal information about You to external organisations in circumstances where We are required or authorised by law, or with Your express consent.

Any credit-related information which We obtain about You from Experian will not be passed onto any banks, credit unions, credit providers or mortgage brokers (“Product Providers”), unless expressly consented to by You.

## Security and storage of Your personal information

### How safe and secure is the information We hold about You?

We take great care with the information We hold about You. Our aim is to ensure that any details are securely protected from misuse, interference and loss, and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. We will take reasonable care to make sure that We keep Your information in an accurate, complete and up-to-date manner.

### What about online security?

The Site is professionally hosted and operates in a secure environment. The Site uses encryption techniques to enhance Your privacy and security when using the Site. You should however be aware that there is always an inherent risk in transmitting Your personal information via the internet.

### How long do We keep information about You?

We will hold Your information for as long as You are an active member of Our service and Our service remains available. Upon termination/cancellation of Your membership, We will remove Your account from Our service within 7 days. Experian may continue to send Us credit-related updates during this time. We may retain Your information for up to 30 days, after which Your information will be destroyed or de-identified.

We may also retain database backups for 12 months which may contain personal information We have collected from You under this Privacy Policy. This information may be retained for the purposes of complying with applicable laws or for Our own security policies. We may continue to retain de-identified information for analytical and reporting purposes.

## Accessing, updating and correcting Your information

### Can You get access to Your information?

It is important for Us, and for You, that the information We hold is accurate and up-to-date. In this, We rely on You to help Us. We allow You to edit certain parts of Your personal information, including Your password, email address and home address details in the Account settings (Manage account) section on the Site. If You wish to update any other information We hold about You (including Your name, if changed), please terminate Your current membership and resubscribe to the Site using Your updated information.

We will not include on Our Site Your previous address details or Your date of birth for security purposes. If You need to access any of Your previous address information, please contact the Privacy Officer using the details under the Contact Us section of this Privacy Policy.

If You wish to access a copy of Your full free Experian credit report, please visit Experian’s website at [www.experian.com.au](http://www.experian.com.au/). If You think there is a mistake then it is important to first check Your credit report which You can obtain from Experian. If any details are wrong, You can ask either Experian or Your credit provider to have them corrected

## Cookies and analytics

### What are cookies?

Cookies are small data files that are downloaded from Our web servers, and stored on Your hard drive. A cookie is a string of letters and numbers that uniquely identify the computer You are using, and the membership details You may have used to register at the Site.

### How we use cookies on our site

Cookies are used on the Site to track Your journey through Our Site and the type of cookie We use contains no personal information at all. This simply allows Us to see at a glance which pages and information is of most interest to visitors and members. Most browsers can be configured to refuse to accept cookies. You can also delete cookies from Your hard drive. However, doing so may hinder Your access to valuable areas of information within Our Site.

We may use “Remarketing” with Google Analytics and other platforms such as Facebook Retargeting to advertise online. This will utilise different cookies. Third-party vendors, including Google, Facebook and media agencies, show Our ads on websites across the Internet. These third-party vendors use the cookies on our Site to inform, optimise and serve ads based on Your past visits to Our Site.

### Google Analytics Advertising Features and cookies it uses

We use Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising. You can opt-out of Google Analytics Advertising Feature by using the [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). In addition, You can use the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to disable tracking by Google Analytics.

We use Google Analytics Demographics and Interest-Reporting to understand the spread of age ranges, gender, and geographic locations of Our users. This enables Us to tailor the Site, content and Our marketing around Our users’ interests.

We may use “Remarketing” with Google Analytics to advertise online. This will utilise different cookies. Third-party vendors, including Google and media agencies, show Our ads on websites across the Internet. These third-party vendors use the cookies on our Site to inform, optimise and serve ads based on Your past visits to Our Site.

## Other important information

### Links to other websites

We provide You with links from the Site to other third party sites. The provision of a link does not imply any endorsement, nor can We accept responsibility for the conduct of third parties linked to Our Site. Once You transfer from the Site to another website, We are not responsible for the conduct or practices of those third party websites. When You transfer to another website and before disclosing Your personal information on that website, You should check the applicable privacy policy of that website.

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time without prior notice to You. Any modifications will be effective immediately upon posting the amended Privacy Policy on the Site. Any subsequent access to, or use by You, of the Site will constitute an acceptance of any varied or modified Privacy Policy. We encourage You to periodically review this Privacy Policy to become aware of any changes that may have occurred.

### Contact Us

Please contact Us if You:

  * have a concern about the handling, use or disclosure of Your personal information;
  * would like further information about the way We manage the personal information that We hold; or
  * wish to access any of Your previous address information that We may hold.

You can do so by sending Us an email at [privacy@creditsavvy.com.au](mailto:privacy@creditsavvy.com.au). Alternatively, You may wish to write to Our Privacy Officer at the following address:

Privacy Officer  
Credit Savvy Australia  
Locked Bag 19 Royal Exchange  
Sydney NSW 1225

Our registered business address is: AHL Investments Pty Ltd, 225 George Street, Level 28, Sydney, NSW 2000

We will make every reasonable effort to investigate Your concern, and notify You of the outcome as quickly as possible. If You are unhappy with Our response, You can contact The Office of the Australian Information Commissioner at:

Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC)  
GPO Box 5218  
Sydney NSW 2001  
Email: [enquiries@oaic.gov.au](mailto:enquiries@oaic.gov.au)
